MELISSA J WOMACK

7510 E Grand Ave, Apt 3322, Dallas, TX 75214 m.womack010101@gmail.com - (512) 568-5185

Summary

Master of Science graduate student at The University of Texas at Dallas in the Bioinformatics and Computational Biology – Computer Science Track program. Teacher's assistant and contributing member of a research lab. Anticipated graduation date of May 2021. Focused on improving skills in programming, algorithm analysis, and data engineering. Previous military experience where I gained soft skills in teamwork, discipline, and adaptability.

Skills

• C++

• Object-Oriented Programming

JavaScript

CSS

Git/GitHub

Microsoft Office

Node.JS

MongoDB

• Java

Mac OS/Linux/Windows OS

• HTML

MySQL

Certifications

Full Stack Web Development Certificate

The University of Texas at Austin

- Curriculum included: MERN Stack, Agile Methodology, API Integration, Responsive Web Design, Git/GitHub, Heroku, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.JS, React.JS, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, and MySQL
- Completed several collaborative and independent projects which can be found here: https://github.com/Melissajwomack

Education

Master of Science in Bioinformatics and Computational Biology

The University of Texas at Dallas, GPA – 3.73

Aug 2019 – Present

July 2018 - Oct 2018

Bachelor of Science in Microbiology

Texas State University, GPA - 3.76, magna cum laude

Aug 2015 - May of 2018

Relevant Coursework

- Algorithm Analysis and Data Structures
- Combinatorics and Graph Theory
- Advanced Calculus and Linear Algebra
- Web Programming Languages Spring 2021
- Computer Science
- Probability and Statistics for Data Science
- Machine Learning Spring 2021
- Database Design Spring 2021

Experience

Microbiology Technician

Clinical Pathology Laboratories, Austin, TX

Feb 2019 - Aug 2019

- Processed and handled over 200 clinical samples a day while adhering to safety protocols and ensuring quality control
- Performed enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays to test for human pathogens in clinical samples
- Assisted in the identification of clinically relevant organisms using a wide array of biochemical tests

Veterinary Food Inspection Specialist

United States Army

April 2007 - Oct 2015

- Collaborated in creating and implementing a database that kept track of 9.3 million dollars of inventory
- Supervised teams of up to 6 people
- Performed the inspection of food designed for human consumption and assisted veterinarians with animal medicine